<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hgs on Carlos León</title>
    <link>https://carlosleon.info/hg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hgs on Carlos León</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 22:25:13 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://carlosleon.info/hg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Every Sled Ride Counts</title>
      <link>https://carlosleon.info/hg/every-sled-ride-counts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 22:25:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carlosleon.info/hg/every-sled-ride-counts/</guid>
      <description>A year ago I went on my first hang gliding trip to the mountains together with the Zenith Aventura hang gliding school from Spain. We went to the French alps. We visited and flew places like Annecy, Col du Sapenay, St. Hilaire, Chamonix and some others that I can&amp;rsquo;t remember anymore.
Back then we were just squabs about to leave the nest but not just yet. Our instructor had us throughout the whole trip doing morning and afternoon flights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First thermal flight ever!</title>
      <link>https://carlosleon.info/hg/first-thermal-flight-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 23:06:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carlosleon.info/hg/first-thermal-flight-ever/</guid>
      <description>I have been waiting for this moment since the very first hang gliding lessons that I took back in March 2015! I know, it&amp;rsquo;s been three seasons all together and not a single time did I get the chance or the permission from my instructors to turn a circle around some raising air.
So far all my flights (about 80 on the winch and 20 on the mountains) had been sled riders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cracking the season 2017 open</title>
      <link>https://carlosleon.info/hg/season-2017-is-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 21:21:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carlosleon.info/hg/season-2017-is-open/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been too long! It&amp;rsquo;s been exactly one year since my last mountain flight. Last time was a lovely 9-days trip to the French Alps with [Zenith Aventura] hang gliding school. It was my first group hang gliding expedision and boy was it fun. Unfortunately I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to fly much more after that. C&amp;rsquo;est la vie.
Now I&amp;rsquo;m back in the game and the season has officially started for me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>